被爱的波浪束缚在雨的房子里，呢喃的情歌，他们说你提供痛苦，但在雷声和美好的外衣之间撕裂
J shackled by the waves of love j within the house of rain j the madrigal of whispering j they say you offer pain j but torn between the thunder j and the undercoat of nice
我漫步在花木和冰塔间甜蜜的美杜莎我想和你玩游戏甜蜜的美杜莎拒绝雨之屋
j I walk among the pimpernels j and towers made of ice j sweet medusa j I'd love to play your game j sweet medusa j deny the house of rain
沙漏原谅过去，致敬太阳，别理会你听到偶像的声音，你赢得了他们的高杯，你鹅卵石的边缘，被风系住
J the hourglass forgives the past j pay tribute to the sun j ignore the idol's voice you hear j their goblets you have won j the edges of your cobblestone j are fastened to the wind
我想和你玩游戏我想和你玩游戏我想和你玩游戏我想和你玩游戏我想和你玩游戏我想和你玩游戏
j repave the mine and drink the wine j the filaments within j sweet medusa j I'd love to play your game j sweet medusa j deny the house of rain j
你不能跟着它跳舞。
You can't dance to it.
嗯，你看，呃……-这是另一种声音。-我不想要不同的声音。
Well, you see, er... - This is a different sound. - Well, I don't want a different sound.
-我们能休息一下吗?——没有。
- Well, can we just play breaks? - No.
-我们给你一个星期50美元。——算了吧!
- We'll give you a week for fifty bucks. - Forget it!
-听着，我们免费给你一个星期!-你不值得。
- Look, we'll give you a week for nothing! - You ain't worth it.
我们要让他跟着跳舞!
We'll give him something he can dance to!
你会拥有城里最有名的俱乐部!
You're gonna have the most famous club in town!
-伙计们，快点!——我会帮助!
- You guys, hurry! - I'll help!
-好吧，好吧!-去死吧，你这个丑陋的混蛋。
- All right, all right! - Drop dead, you ugly bastard.
我想这个标志现在终于拼出来了。
I think that sign's finally spelled right now.
千变万化的风，呼唤着我的名字，向我招手，“来吧”
J winds of change, they call my name j and beckon, "come"
就像飞蛾扑火一样
j just like a moth to a flame
春天的孩子，圣经带给你的一切，不要折断锁链中的一环
j child of spring j the scriptures bring you everything j don't break the link in the chain
神奇轮在哪里?
j and wherein lies the wonderwheel?
>我们都被安排如何去感受&哦，妈妈，不要等我…＆
> We've all been structured how to feel & oh, mama j j don't you wait up for me... &
是的，我知道你的意思。
yes, I know what you mean.
——再见,妈妈。-克罗利夫人为你在医院帮忙感到骄傲
- Bye, mom. - Mrs crowley's proud of you helping out at the hospital.
是的，她在路上了，克劳力太太。
Yes, she's on her way, mrs crowley.
再见,爸爸。
Bye, daddy.
哦。噢,谢谢你。
Oh. Oh, thank you.
-吃早餐怎么样?-我不饿。
- How about some breakfast? - I'm not hungry.
昨天，风笛手吹着琴声，把我抱起一个朴素的影子之子
J yesterday, the Piper played > and lifted me j a simple child of the shade
小个子，我知道他拉着你的手，在林间空地上划出一条路
j little man, I understand j he took your hand j and marked a path through the glade
神奇轮在哪里?
j and wherein lies the wonderwheel?
>我们都被安排如何感受j哦，妈妈j你不要等我不，妈妈j哦!
> We've all been structured how to feel j oh, mama j don't you wait up for me j no, mama j oh!
别跟着我不，妈妈我要去看世界了你好，孩子们。
J don't try to follow me j no, mama j I'm off to see the world j hiya, boys.
嗨,艾略特。
Hi, Elliot.
嗨,马克西。你会在哪里?
Hi, maxie. Where ya goin'?
我应该在医院工作的。
Oh, I'm supposed to work over at the hospital.
不如你在我家停一下吧?
Why don't you stop over at my place, huh?
嗯?
Mmm?
她爱你，耶，耶，耶-耶，耶，耶，耶，再来一次!
J she loves you, yeah, yeah, yeah - s yeah j J yeah, yeah, yeah j one more time!
她爱你，耶，耶，耶&她爱你，耶，耶…j
J she loves you, yeah, yeah, yeah & she loves you, yeah, yeah... j
停止!
Stop that!
你父亲回来了。
Your father's home.
我们去看看他带了什么!
Let's go see what he's got!
噢,瞧!哦,我的上帝!
Oh, look! Oh, my god!
哦，看那些鸭子!
Oh, look at the duckies!
哦,亚瑟!哦，看看你!
Oh, Arthur! Oh, look at you!
快来看鸭子!
Come see the ducks!
嘿，大卫，怎么样?
Hey, David, how about that?
哦,马克西!
Oh, maxie!
哎呀，我得小心点。我会让你血淋淋的。
Whoops, I gotta be careful. I'll get you all bloody.
-你有多少?- 12。
- How many d'you get? - Twelve, altogether.
哇!大卫，你怎么从来没做过这种事?
Wow! David, why don't you ever do a thing like that?
-我以为上限是三个。-如果我们被抓的话
- I thought the limit was three. - That's if we get caught.
实际上，有14个!
Actually, there were fourteen!
另外两个呢?
What happened to the other two?
他们是跛子帮。他们成群结队地跑到草丛中去了。
They were crips. They flocked off into the weeds.
亚瑟，他们不会受苦太久的，对吧?
Arthur, they won't suffer long, will they?
哦,不,不。有狐狸可能会抓到他们。
Oh, no, no. Some fox'll probably get 'em.
-狐狸也得吃东西，你知道的。-给你，梅森先生。
- Foxes have to eat too, ya know. - Here, mr Mason.
-我帮你把它们拿到厨房去。-谢谢你，桑迪。
- Let me take 'em into the kitchen for you. - Oh, thank you, Sandy.
哦，我儿子真棒，不是吗?
Oh, isn't my son wonderful?
说到儿子，我想知道我们的儿子怎么样了?阿蒂?
Speaking of sons, I wonder what's become of ours? Artie?
——……他感觉不舒服。-他头痛。
- He's... he's not feeling well. - He has a headache.
带着十五磅的头发到处跑，谁都会头疼的。-他是不是很有趣?亚瑟，你真有趣!
Well, carrying fifteen pounds of hair around - would give anybody a headache. - Isn't he funny? Arthur, you're so funny!
我想我们得走了。来吧,蒂娜。
Well, I think we gotta go. Come on, Tina.
我们走吧。该走了。
Let's go. It's time to go.
他爱我，耶，耶，耶，耶…j
J he loves me, yeah, yeah, yeah j j loves me, yeah, yeah... j
艺术吗?阿蒂?
Art? Artie?
阿蒂?
Artie?
嘿,灌木头骨!
Hey, shrubbery skull!
快下来，我们在吃晚饭。
Come on down, we're having dinner.
嘿,mop-head !“亚瑟……现在,我…我只是想让他下来
Hey, mop-head! “Arthur... Now, what I'm... All I'm doing is asking him to come down.
快下来，阿图罗!
Come on down, Arturo!
那他为什么不下来呢?
Well, why doesn't he come down?
烤鸭!
Roast duck!
和幸福。
And happiness.
现在,阿蒂…阿蒂?向下走!
Now, Artie... Artie? Come on down!
我不太饿。
I'm not very hungry.
如果你不想吃，至少…把你的头发放下来!
Well, if you don't wanna eat, at least send... Send your hair down!
我想他想练习。
I think he wants to practise.
实践中,嗯?他是这么说的吗?
Practice, huh? Is that what he calls it?
地狱!加油,亚瑟!
Hell! Come on, Arthur!
-别这样，亲爱的。-好吧，但为什么这么自私?
- Come on now, honey. - All right, but why be selfish?
没必要让他的头发挨饿!
No need for his hair to starve!
你为什么就不能让他好好想想他的头发?
Why can't you leave him alone about his hair?
只是因为它的长度和你的不一样!
Just because it isn't the same length as yours!
我到底做了什么?
What the hell did I do?
你们俩什么时候才能停止调音开始演奏?
When are you two gonna stop tuning up and start playing something?
来吧，姐姐，我们放点真正的音乐。
Come on, sis, let's play some real music.
我有音乐，我有我的女孩，谁能要求更多?
J I got music j I got my gal j who could ask for anything more?
- J我有雏菊…j - Jlgotlala…这就是我所谓的音乐!
- J I got daisies... j - Jlgotlala...D that's what I call music!
桑迪带来了一些奶酪蛋糕。
Sandy brought some cheesecake.
很好。他们只是为了逗老人开心，桑迪。
Fine. They're just playing this to amuse the old man, Sandy.
他们不喜欢是因为它有旋律。
They don't like it because it has a melody.
我打赌他们比你想的更喜欢，梅森先生。
You know, I bet they like it better than you think, mr Mason.
我有星光，我有美梦，来加入吧!
J' I got starlight, I got sweet dreams j come on and join in!
-不，不，我得走了-谢谢你的芝士蛋糕，桑迪。
- No, no, I gotta be goin'. - Thanks for the cheesecake, Sandy.
谁能要求更多?这才是你应该玩的东西。
J who could ask for anything more? J now that's the kinda stuff you oughta play.
人们想听的东西。
The kinda stuff people wanna hear.
其他的东西，没人会付你一分钱的。
That other stuff, nobody'll pay you a dime for that.
-爸爸，让我告诉你…-马克西，算了
- Dad, let me tell you something... - Oh, maxie, never mind.
既然万能的美元是你判断一切的方式，我有消息告诉你。
Since the almighty dollar is your way of judging everything, I've got news for you.
阿迪和他的团队找到了一份工作，从今晚开始，周薪200。
Artie and his group have got a job, starting tonight, paying two hundred a week.
阿迪，是真的吗?
Artie, is that true?
我本打算今晚穿上戏服告诉你的，但是…但是那太好了!
Yeah, well, I was gonna tell you tonight, when I had my costume on, but... But that's wonderful!
200美元，对吧?
Two hundred bucks, huh?
有些人钱比脑子还多。
Well, some people have more money than brains.
五角大楼今天说，目前的行动是美国和南越合作的一个例子，把越共赶出关键的水稻种植区。
Pentagon said today that the present operation is an example of American and south vietnamese co-operation, driving the viet cong out of critical rice-growing areas.
前进中的美军部队在猛烈的轻武器火力下占领了前沿阵地。你在开玩笑吧。
Advancing American units seized forward positions under intense small-arms fire... You gotta be kidding.
你不会就这样跑到街上去吧?
You're not going out on the street like that, are ya?
文明到底发生了什么?
Whatever happened to civilisation?
这是我们关系的一部分。
It's part of our thing, you know.
你的事情,嗯?
Your thing, huh?
好吧，你可能很快就会做他们的事了，所以你还是趁现在好好享受吧。
Well, you'll probably be doing their thing soon, so you might as well have fun while you can.
把那玩意儿关了，好吗?我受够了。
Oh, shut that stuff off, will ya? I'm sick of it.
砰,砰,砰。
Bang, bang, bang.
好吧,再见。
Well, so long.
亚瑟!
Arthur!
亚瑟!请你过来一下好吗?很快!
Arthur! Will you come here, please? Quickly!
-怎么了?——请快点。
- What's the matter? - Please, hurry.
-什么事?-我不喜欢。
- What is it? - I don't like it.
太远了。太远了。
It's too far. Too far.
我想回家!
I wanna go home!
我听说山。
I hear mountains.
-搞什么鬼?-我听到山的声音。我…——亲爱的,亲爱的…——山!山!
- What the hell? - I hear mountains. I... - Darling, darling... - Mountains! Mountains!
亲爱的,回去。甚至不看看。让我来处理。
Go back, sweetheart. Don't even look. Let me handle this.
我一切都好。我真的害怕。
I'm all right. I really am.
我马上就回来。别担心。
I'll be back. Don't worry.
你在里面搞什么鬼?
What the devil are you doing in there?
我寻找。我明白了。
I'm looking. I see.
看着我。
Look at me.
哦，往高处走!看到我!
Oh, way, way up! See me!
——看!-马克西，快出来
- Look! - Maxie, come on outta there.
——亚瑟……——她是喝醉了。
- Arthur... - She's drunk.
亲爱的,亲爱的…我看到的音乐。
Darling, darling... I see music.
看!
Look!
看!看这音乐!
Look! Look at the music!
她绊倒。“什么?她是什么?
She's tripping. “What? She's what?
这是好的,马克西。
It's okay, maxie.
阿蒂在这里。别担心。
Artie's here. Don't worry.
阿蒂!
Artie!
甜蜜的吉他!
Sweet guitar!
甜美，甜美，甜美的吉他。
Sweet, sweet, sweet guitar.
你在说什么?她怎么了?
What are you talkin' about? What's the matter with her?
你能安静一分钟吗?你听说过LSD吗?
Can you be quiet for a minute? Have you ever heard of LSD?
-我想回家-没关系，马克西。没关系。
- I wanna go home. - It's okay, maxie. It's okay.
马克西，你拿了多少?
Maxie, how much did you take?
并不多。我没拿多少。
Not much. I didn't take much.
LSD ? !
LSD?!
把我带回来。我想回来。我很害怕。
Bring me back. I wanna come back. I'm scared.
山来了。
The mountain's coming.
山来了!
The mountain's coming!
神……
God...
我电!
I'm electric!
我电!我…阿蒂的丫。别担心。
I'm electric! I'm... Artie's with ya. Don't worry.
这座山不会伤害你。
The mountain won't hurt you.
来吧,现在。
Come on, now.
跟阿迪走，回你自己的床上。
Walk with Artie, to your own bed.
-来吧，现在。-来吧，宝贝。
- Come on, now. - Come on, baby.
我想回家。我想要我爸爸。
I wanna go home. I want my daddy.
我想要我爸爸。爸爸!
I want my daddy. Daddy!
你爸爸来了，宝贝。在这里。
Your daddy's here, baby. Right here.
刀片!
Razor blades!
没关系。没事的，阿迪和你在一起。
It's okay. It's okay, Artie's with ya.
阿迪会带你回家的。
Artie's gonna get ya home.
-拿些安眠药。-我不应该叫医生吗?
- Get some sleeping pills. - Shouldn't I call the doctor?
不要叫任何人。照他说的做。去拿安眠药。
Don't call anybody. Do like he says. Get the sleeping pills.
马克西,来吧。
Maxie, come on.
你自己的小床。
Your own little bed.
安全的在家里。来吧。
Safe at home. Come on.
安全的在家里。躺在你自己的小床上。
Safe at home. Nice and soft, in your own little bed.
床上?床上?
Bed? Bed?!
-阿迪会带你回家的,就…试试……-它们有多强壮?-上面写着睡觉用的。
- Artie's gonna get you home. - Just... just try... - How strong are they? - It says one for sleep.
给我两个。
Let me have two.
那是谁?
Who's that?
那是谁? !
Who's that?!
我想和你谈谈。
I wanna talk to you.
爸，我跟她说话的时候你得保持安静。我很抱歉。
Dad, you're just gonna have to be quiet while I'm talking her down. I'm sorry.
给你，马克西。
Here ya are, maxie.
给你几顶帽子。
Couple of caps for ya.
嘿,机票回家。
Hey, tickets home.
来吧,现在。
Come on, now.
机票回家。
Tickets home.
你知道谁在这里吗?
Now, you know who's here?
你的妈妈在这里。
Your mom's here.
那不是很好吗?
Isn't that nice?
妈妈……
Mom...
-我很冷，妈妈。-妈妈和你在一起。Sssssh。
- I'm cold, mom. - Mommy's with you. Sssssh.
继续和她说话，妈妈。如果我们能让她睡着，几小时后她就会没事了。
Just keep talking to her, mom. If we can get her to sleep, she oughta be okay in a couple of hours.
-我冷…-妈妈给你准备了一条暖和的毯子。
- I'm cold... - Mommy's got a warm blanket for you.
——会回家吗?-是的，亲爱的，回家去。
- Goin' home? - Yes, darling, going home.
-回家吗，妈妈?——是的,宝贝。
- Goin' home, momma? - Yes, sweetheart.
——会回家吗?-是的，亲爱的。嘘!是的,宝贝。
- Goin' home? - Yes, my darling. Sssh. Yes, baby.
- Sssssh…-我想和你谈谈。现在!
- Sssssh... - I wanna talk to you. Now!
-是的，亲爱的。-我很冷，妈妈。
- Yes, my darling. - I'm cold, mom.
Ssh……嘿…-你还有那种东西吗?-爸，你得相信我…我不喜欢。清空你的口袋。
Ssh... Hey... - Hey, you got any more of that stuff? - Dad, you gotta believe me... I don't. Empty your pockets.
-我发誓…-我说了清空它们!
- I swear... - I said empty 'em!
不。
No.
那么，该死的，我会的。
Then, goddamn it, I will.
她开始跟你那帮怪胎混在一起的时候我就知道会发生这样的事。
I knew something like this was gonna happen when she started hanging out with that freaky gang of yours.
肯定就在这里。
It's gotta be in here somewhere.
你妈妈会把你的衣服送到你工作的那家变态酒吧。
Your mother'll send your clothes to that freak joint where you work.
你别再回来了，永远别。做任何事情!
You're not comin' back here, ever. For anything!
离你妹妹远点，听见了吗?
And stay away from your sister, do you hear?
你……你给我听好了，你个废物!
You... Now, you listen to me, you no-good punk!
如果你妹妹因此受到任何伤害，任何永久性的伤害，你最好快跑，因为我会追上你，我会打断你的每一根骨头!
If your sister suffers any kind of damage because of this, any permanent damage, you better start runnin', because I'm comin' after you, and I'll break every bone in your body!
我不再尊重你了。
I don't respect you anymore.
我想她要睡觉了。
I think she's going to sleep.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
-我把他赶出去了。——不!
- I kicked him out. - No!
的小朋克。阿蒂!
Freaky little punk. Artie!
她为什么要拿走那些东西?
Why would she take that stuff, anyhow?
她是不是疯了?
Is she nuts or somethin'?
完美的孩子，正常的孩子，什么都有。
Perfect kid, normal as they come, a kid who's got everything.
我觉得我们应该找人谈谈。
I think we ought to talk to somebody.
谁?谁?一头收缩机吗?绝对不是。
Who? Who? A head shrinker? Absolutely not.
大卫呢?
What about David?
我不会让隔壁的人干涉我的私生活!——亚瑟,请。
I'm not getting the people next door - involved in my private life! - Arthur, please.
-我要她去睡觉。-听着，gerrie，如果你觉得你必须在某个时候向David求助…
…-求助大卫?-我就是这么说的。
- I want her to go to sleep. - Listen, gerrie, if you feel you have to turn to... To David at a time like... - Turn to David? - That's what I said.
-我们需要建议。-你不相信我的判断?
- We need advice. - You don't trust my judgement?
这不是你的东西，亚瑟。
Oh, it's not your anything, Arthur.
这是我们的。
It's our.
我们失败。我们必须面对这一点。
We're failing. We have to face that.
如果你想去找蒂娜和大卫，就去吧!
Look, if you wanna go to Tina and David, you go!
让我告诉你一件事。
Lemme tell you one thing.
我不会为之后发生的任何事负责。
I'm not taking the responsibility for anything that happens after that.
明白了吗?这是你的责任。
Is that clear? It's your responsibility.
去做吧。走了。
Go ahead. Go.
你知道吗，亚瑟?
You know something, Arthur?
每次我们遇到危机，需要做决定的时候，你都会对我发火。
Every time we come to any kind of a crisis, where... Where a decision has got to be made, you get furious at me.
这是一个谎言。
That's a lie.
并拒绝承担任何责任。
And refuse to take any responsibility.
那是谎话，你知道的。
That's a damn lie, and you know it.
我要去隔壁。
I'm going next door.
你这样做。
You do that.
嘿，格里，你和亚瑟一会儿回家吗?
Hey there, gerrie, are you and Arthur going to be home later?
哦……哦,是的。是的,我想象。
Oh... oh, yes. Yes, I imagine.
今晚电视上没什么节目，所以格洛丽亚和我想我们还是通过一杯马提尼来看看你和亚瑟吧。你觉得呢?
Well, there's nothing much doing on TV tonight, so Gloria and I thought we'd rather look at you and Arthur through a Martini. What do you think?
大约半小时后，好吗?gerrie ?
In about a half hour, okay? Okay, gerrie?
她生我们的气了吗?
Is she mad at us?
你又吃她的天竺葵了吗?
Have you been eating her geraniums again?
——梅森太太!——哦,桑迪。
- Mrs Mason! - Oh, Sandy.
-出什么事了吗?——哦，好吧...算是吧。
- Is there something wrong? - Oh, well... sort of.
你父亲在家吗?
Is your father home?
你知道妈妈，她晚饭后有时会有点困。
You know mom, she gets kinda sleepy after dinner sometimes.
呃…天，不，爸爸去学校了。
Er... gee, no, dad's over at the school.
发生了骚乱。
There's been a riot.
他说什么了?
What did he say?
他在学校。
He's at the school.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
你认为我们应该吗?
Do you think we ought to?
冰之塔美杜莎美杜莎我很想玩你的游戏美杜莎美杜莎拒绝雨之屋你以为你是谁?
J towers made of ice j sweet medusa j I'd love to play your game j sweet medusa j deny the house of rain j who do you think you are?
法西斯猪!
Fascist pigs!
你没有搜查令!
You ain't got no warrant!
胡志明!胡志明!
Ho chi minh! Ho chi minh!
-滚出去!-小心玻璃。
- Get outta here! - Watch the glass.
喂!喂!胡志明!
Ho! Ho! Ho chi minh!
我们谁也赢不了!
None of us is gonna win!
喂!喂!胡志明!
Ho! Ho! Ho chi minh!
别碰我!你以为你是谁?!
Get your hands off of me! Who do you think you are?!
——噢,嗨。- - - - - -大卫。
- Oh, hi. - David.
我的一些学生明年上大学需要这些记录。-这太可怕了。
Some of my students are gonna need these records - to get into college next year. - This is terrible.
-我们不应该打扰你。-没事的。一切都结束了。
- We shouldn't be bothering you. - It's all right. It's all over.
现在只是一项清理工作。亚瑟……
It's just a clean-up job now. Arthur...
格里在电话里把细节都告诉我了。
Gerrie told me the bare details on the phone.
看看他们对你的办公室做了什么，大卫，而你是校长。
Look what they did to your office, David, and you're the principal.
大卫，你为这个世界上的孩子们做了什么?
David, what the hell do you do for kids in this world?
我们尽了一切可能。
We did everything humanly possible.
我是说，我们给她上了网球课，钢琴课，拉拉队，温馨的家，温馨的邻居。
I mean, we gave her tennis lessons, piano lessons, cheerleader, good home, good neighbourhood.
-给她爱。——爱?我们当然给了她爱。
- Gave her love. - Love? Of course we gave her love.
我知道，我知道。
I know, I know.
如果我们是一群神经质的…你知道我的意思. 那我就能理解了，但是……对不起，格里。你想坐下吗?
If we were a neurotic bunch of... You know what I mean. Then I could understand, but... Oh, excuse me, gerrie. Would you like to sit down?
不,我很好。
No, I'm fine.
在我们开始前你想喝点咖啡吗?
Would you like some coffee before we start?
哦,是的,请。只是黑色的。
Oh, yes, please. Just black.
你有一角硬币吗?是的。
Do you have a dime? Yes.
我不敢看他们在图书馆做的事，但我必须看。
I'm afraid to look at what they did in the library, but I've got to.
你觉得怎么样?正对着门。
How about that? Right through the door.
他们终于找到了书籍的用处。
They finally found a use for books.
哦,在这里,大卫。
Oh, here, David.
我不明白他们为什么不毁掉咖啡机。
I can't understand why they didn't destroy the coffee machine.
连我都同意咖啡机是资产阶级的阴谋。
Even I agree the coffee machine is a bourgeois plot.
我想玩你的游戏
J the filaments within j sweet medusa j I'd like to play your game j
我们的孩子什么事都可以来找我们。他们知道。
our children can come to us about anything. They know that.
如果他能让她说出内心的真实想法。
If he can get her to really say what she thinks, deep down.
-我就是这个意思。——他是对的。
- That's what I mean. - He's right.
她没说的那些事可能是因为她觉得你不想让她说。
All the things she may not have said because she may have thought that you didn't want her to.
但是我们做的!
But we did!
但你真的想这么做吗，亲爱的?
But did you really want to, sweetheart?
还是你害怕了?讲真话。
Or were you afraid? Tell the truth.
我…我必须承认是我自己的错，因为我没有早点坚持。但是…亲爱的，你会喜欢的。
I... I have to admit that I was at fault myself, because I didn't insist on it sooner. But... Oh, sweetheart, you're going to enjoy it.
你会比你想象的更了解你的女儿。
You'll get to know your daughter better than you ever dreamed possible.
听着，我不知道我们俩能不能受得了，但是…Geronimo !
Listen, I don't know if either one of us is gonna be able to stand it, but... Geronimo!
它就在我们身边，格里。
It's all around us, gerrie.
他们想让我们整个社会重新振作起来，动摇它，然后看看有什么会被淘汰。至少健康的人会。
They wanna pick our whole society up by the heels and shake it, and see what drops out. At least the healthy ones do.
其他人只是想摆脱它，用最好的方式。
The others just wanna try to get away from it, the best way they can.
是的,用药物。
Yeah, with drugs.
亲爱的，说起来好笑，我们很幸运。
Oh, sweetheart, in a funny way, we're lucky.
我们……我们一开始就发现了。
We... we caught this thing at the very beginning.
好吧，我们的儿子死于这种疾病，或者疯狂，或者其他什么，但我们不能失去我们的女儿。
All right, we lost our son to this sickness, or craziness, or whatever it is, but we're not going to lose our little girl.
你好，电动踏板。
Hello, electric crash pad.
你好。
Hello.
我不明白你的意思，亲爱的。
I can't understand you, honey.
谁?
Who?
阿蒂?
Artie?
他是音乐家之一吗?
Is he one of the musicians?
有个醉鬼想给管风琴手留个口信。
Some drunk broad wants to leave a message for the organ player.
挂断电话!
Hang up!
喂?
Hello?
哦……
Oh...
我真希望能和拉弗蒂联系上。
I wish to hell I could get in touch with Rafferty.
我会取消那该死的网球比赛。
I'd cancel that damn tennis match.
我都睡不着了。
I'm not gonna get a wink of sleep.
网球!
Tennis!
我还能有什么条件反射?
What kinda reflexes am I gonna have?
马克西!马克西!
Maxie! Maxie!
哦,亲爱的。
Oh, darling.
一切……一切都是好的。
Everything's... Everything's all right.
现在没什么好哭的了。
There's nothing to cry about now.
亲爱的，那是个错误。
Darling, it was a mistake.
任何人都可能犯错误。
Anybody can make a mistake.
我们会忘记这一切的。
We're going to forget that it ever happened.
现在,。现在,现在,亲爱的。一切都是好的。
There, now. Now, now, darling. Everything's all right.
-不是吗，爸爸?-是的，宝贝，一切都好。
- Isn't it, daddy? - Yes, baby, everything's fine.
——很好。-我没办法。
- Just fine. - I can't help it.
亲爱的，试着停下来一会儿。
Well, darling, try to stop for a minute.
爸爸和我想跟你谈谈。
Daddy and I want to talk to you.
不是现在。请,不是现在。
Not now. Please, not now.
-你想继续睡觉吗?——不,我…我不能。
- Do you wanna go back to sleep? - No, I... I can't.
你有什么特别的事在哭吗?
Is there any particular thing you're crying about?
-宝贝，一切都好。-不，我只是想哭。
- Baby, everything's fine. - No, I just feel like crying.
来……
Come...
宝贝,我…
Baby, I...
-也许你该回去睡觉。-我不想睡觉
- Maybe if you went back to sleep. - I don't wanna sleep.
我要坐起来等阿迪。
I'm gonna sit up and wait for Artie.
-亲爱的…-让我来处理
- Darling... - Let me handle this.
马克西……马克西，我们知道那是阿迪给你带来的。
Maxie... Maxie, we know Artie brought you that stuff.
你做了什么?
What have you done?
——嗯…-我把他打发走了
- Well... - I sent him away.
阿蒂?
Artie?
-你把他赶出去了?-你父亲觉得…我们知道你有多爱你哥哥。
- You kicked him out? - Well, your father felt that... We know how much you love your brother.
别忘了，他是我们的儿子。
He's our son, don't forget.
这对我们来说也很难。……这对你父亲来说很难，比你想象的难多了。
This is hard for us, too. It's... it's hard for your father, much harder than you think.
你知道你是什么吗，爸爸?
You know what you are, daddy?
你是一个愚蠢的人。
You're a jackass.
她是想保护他。总是这样。
She's trying to protect him. It's always like this.
他撒谎，她也发誓。
He lies, and she swears to it.
你们都是愚蠢的。
You're both jackasses.
我想我们应该等到明天再谈。
I think we ought to wait till tomorrow to talk about it.
我觉得我们现在应该谈谈。
I think we ought to talk about it right now.
你不会喜欢的。
You're not going to like it.
我能来一口吗?
May I have a drag of that?
我不知道你抽烟。
I didn't know you smoked.
还有很多你不知道的。
There's a lot you don't know.
说吧。
Go ahead.
这不是我第一次被绊倒了。
This is not the first time I've tripped out.
我至少醒过十五次。
I've been up at least fifteen times.
我不相信你。我不相信你。
I don't believe you. I don't believe you.
所有的套路我都试过了，骑马都试过，但迷幻药是我的最爱。
I've tried all the grooves, even horse, but acid's my scene.
你……你说像…你从哪里得到这些词的?
You... you talk like... Where did you get these words?
这是我，爸爸。
This is me, daddy.
这就是我。
This is me.
我女儿生病了。我的小女儿病了。
My daughter's sick. My little girl is sick.
我没有生病。你。
I'm not sick. You are.
-所以你才这么痛苦。-我不痛苦。
- That's why you're so miserable. - I'm not miserable.
至少，我没有。
At least, I wasn't.
你知道吗，你应该少吃点迷幻药。
You know, you oughta drop a little acid.
像……看到上帝，妈妈。
Like... See god, mom.
看到上帝,不是吗?
See god, huh?
当我们在壁橱里发现你时，你真的看到了上帝。
You were really seeing god when we found you in that closet.
我经历了一次糟糕的旅行。这可能发生。
I was on a bad trip. That can happen.
不该用我的迷幻药。
Shouldn't have taken speed with my acid.
亚瑟，我要生病了。我得离开这里。
Arthur, I'm going to be ill. I have to get out of here.
不，亲爱的，听我说。
No, darling, listen to me.
,但是……-不，你就坐在这里。
- But... - No, you just sit down here.
给我。
Gimme that.
除了你那怪胎哥哥的影响，是什么让你开始做这个的?
Now, aside from your freaky brother's influence, what got you started on this stuff?
我哥哥的影响一直是让我不要再管这事了。
My brother's influence has always been to tell me to leave this whole scene alone.
我不相信，但你说啊。
I don't believe that, but go ahead.
我服用迷幻药是因为我想成为一个更好的人。
I took acid because I wanted to be a better person.
这是成为更好的人的好方法，好吗。
It's a fine way to be a better person, all right.
我想也是因为你和…妈妈和整个世界总是让我紧张。
And also, I guess, because you and... Mom and the world in general just keep me uptight all the time.
我们让你很紧张，是吗?
We keep you uptight, do we?
什么……我们怎么做呢?
What... now, how do we do that?
只是因为太荒唐了。
Just by being ridiculous.
你知道，愚蠢，虚伪。
You know, dumb, phoney.
你……换句话说，你恨我们。
You... In other words, you hate us.
是的,我……我想是的。
Yes, I... I think so.
你说我们很蠢。Waell……你能给我举个例子吗?
You say we're dumb. Waell... Can you give me an example?
就像我告诉你的，你相信。
Well, like everything I tell you, you believe.
例如呢?
For instance?
比如，如果我告诉你其中一个孩子很好，你俩都会说，哦，很好。
Like if I tell you one of the kids is nice, you both say, "oh, that's nice.
“然后你可以在那里过夜，因为那是一个很好的家庭。”
"Then you can spend the night over there because it's a nice family."
那孩子可能是你见过的最大的头。
And that kid might be the biggest head you ever saw.
换句话说，信任就是做一个傻瓜。
In other words, to trust is to be a fool.
你是个变态的人。
You are a sick person.
妈，我们没谈过我的性生活。
Mom, we didn't talk about my sex life.
有什么事吗?你不敢问吗?
What's the matter? You scared to ask?
你最大的怀疑是真的
Well, your worst suspicions are true.
你相信吗，今天早上?
Would you believe, this morning?
我不像你想的那样在医院。
I wasn't at the hospital like you thought.
我和一个男孩在一起。
I was with a boy.
你知道,做爱。
You know, fucking.
什么男孩?
What boy?
你想伤害他，对吧?
You'd try to hurt him, wouldn't you?
你才十六岁!
You're sixteen years old!
哦,狗屎。
Oh, shit.
是那个叫艾略特的小子，对吧?
It was that Elliot boy, wasn't it?
对不起，爸爸，这事我只好让步了。
Sorry, daddy, I'll have to take the fifth on that.
不管怎样，在他前面还有一个。
Anyhow, there was another one before him.
已经有一年多了
For more than a year now.
别担心，妈妈，我不会有孩子的。
Oh, don't worry, mom, I'm not gonna have a baby.
我吃了避孕药。
I'm on the pill.
你……在哪里?
Where would you...?
你十六岁。你从哪儿弄来的?
You're sixteen. Where would you get such a thing?
很容易。所有的女孩都有。
It's easy. All the girls have 'em.
那些想要他们的人。
Ones that want them.
-我疯了吗?——没有。
- Am I losing my mind? - No.
-是我造成的吗?——没有。你真是个好妈妈。
- Did I cause this? - No. You've been a good mother.
我不会让你承担这一切的责任。
I'm not gonna let you take the blame for this.
她一点都不好，就是这样，她太坏了。
She's no good, that's all, she's rotten.
-家庭中有时也会发生。-她病了，她病了
- It happens in a family sometimes. - Oh, she's sick, she's sick.
你和爸爸在结婚前就这么做了。
You and daddy did it before you were married.
我听你说过。
I heard you talking about it.
你还记得莎伦吗，她去年常来我家过夜?
You remember Sharon, that used to come and spend the night with me last year?
伯纳德博士的女儿。
Dr Bernard's daughter.
她常常带着她父亲的听诊器，我们走进大厅，把听诊器挂在你卧室的门上。
Well, she used to bring her father's stethoscope, and we'd go into the hall and put the stethoscope on your bedroom door.
爸爸!
Daddy!
-我们得带她去看医生-她没病，她疯了
- We've got to get her to a doctor. - She's not sick, she's crazy.
——亚瑟……-现在的孩子都很疯狂!
- Arthur... - Kids nowadays are crazy!
难道你不明白吗?如果她没病，就不会发生这种事。
Don't you understand? If she weren't sick, this couldn't happen.
这是不可能发生的。
It just couldn't happen.
我得睡一会儿。
I gotta get some sleep.
千变万化的风，呼唤着我的名字，向我招手，“来吧”
J winds of change, they call my name j and beckon, "come"
就像飞蛾扑火一样
j just like a moth to a flame
春天的孩子，圣经带给你的一切，不要折断锁链中的一环
j child of spring j the scriptures bring you everything j don't break the link in the chain
神奇轮在哪里?
j and wherein lies the wonderwheel?
>我们都被安排好如何感受j哦，妈妈j你不要等我不，妈妈j不要试着跟着我j不，妈妈j我要去看世界j
> We've all been structured how to feel j oh, mama j don't you wait up for me j no, mama j don't try to follow me j no, mama j I'm off to see the world j
_elliot吗?
_elliot?
嘿,是我。
Hey, it's me.
我不会跟他们回去的，永远不会。
I'm not going back with them, ever.
是的。
Yeah.
嘿…你嗑药了?
Hey... You stoned?
——什么?——嗯?
- On what? - Hmm?
什么?
What?
来吧。
Come on.
昨天，吹笛人吹着琴声把我抱起，我明白他拉着我的手，划出一条穿过林间空地的路，神奇的轮子在哪里?＆
J yesterday, the Piper played > and lifted me j a simple child of the shade j little man, I understand j he took my hand & and marked a path through the glade j &' and wherein lies the wonderwheel? &
>我们都被安排好如何感受j哦，妈妈j你不要等我不，妈妈j不要试着跟着我j不，妈妈j我要去看世界j _arthur!
> we've all been structured how to feel j oh, mama j don't you wait up for me j no, mama j don't try to follow me j no, mama j I'm off to see j the world j _arthur!
阿迪会知道她在哪的。
Artie'll know where she is.
你看看这个!
Will you look at this!
他知道这个地方，他知道。他直接来了。
He knows this place, knows it. He came straight here.
我该去哪里?
Where do I go?
-我带你去。-不，告诉我
- I'll show you. - No, just tell me.
-二楼，右边最后一个门。——亚瑟。
- Second floor, last door on the right. - Arthur.
亲爱的,在这里。我不想让你看到这个。
Darling, stay here. I don't want you to see this.
亚瑟,小心些而已。
Arthur, be careful.
——几楼?——第二。
- What floor? - Second.
和你妈妈待在一起。
Stay with your mother.
你给我滚，莱尼!滚出去!
You get outta here, Lenny! Get out!
滚出去!
Get out!
你是红十字会的吗，伙计?
Hey, you from the red cross, man?
我们已经给了。
We gave already.
马克西在哪儿?
Where's maxie?
马克西吗?
Maxie?
我不认识马克西。
I don't know no maxie.
你很了解她。她经常来这里。
You know her all right. She comes here all the time.
她也是未成年人。
She's a minor, too.
所以你最好告诉我她在哪里，而且动作要快，否则你会进监狱的。
So, you better tell me where she is, and do it fast, or you're gonna end up in jail.
嘿，我没见过任何人，好吗?
Hey, I ain't seen nobody, okay?
我会回来，还有警察!
I'm comin' back, with cops!
爸爸!
Daddy!
你这个愚蠢的疯子!
You stupid, freaked-out head!
为什么,你……离我远点。
Why, you... Keep away from me.
离我远点。
Keep away from me.
怎么了，爸爸?
What's the matter, daddy?
嗯,你害怕吗?
You scared, huh?
嗯?你很害怕，是吗?不是吗? !
Huh? You're scared, aren't you? Aren't you?!
爸爸怕了。
Daddy's scared.
爸爸怕了!
Daddy's scared!
看他!
Look at him!
我会再跑掉的，越快越好。
I'll run away again, just as soon as I can.
梅森先生?是的。劳伦博士吗?
Mr Mason? Yes. Dr Lauren?
是的,请进。坐下来。
Yeah, come in. Sit down.
呃…卡罗尔，你想给梅森先生留杯咖啡吗?
Er... Carol, you want to leave a coffee for mr Mason?
不,谢谢。
No, thanks.
哦，没关系。我可以再买一些。
Oh, it's all right. I can get some more.
-不，真的，谢谢。——好的。再见。
- No, really, thank you. - Okay. Bye-bye.
坐下来。
Sit down.
根据你在电话里跟我说的，我应该直接跟孩子的父亲谈谈。
Well, from what you told me about this boy on the phone, I should talk directly to the father.
哦，那是不可能的。
Oh, that'll never happen.
相信我，我认识这个人。
Believe me, I know this guy.
不，我是在想，通过和你谈话，我能更好地知道该怎么跟他说。
No, I was thinking that, by talking to you, I'll get a better idea of what to tell him.
你知道，一些明智的建议。
You know, some sensible advice.
跟我说说这个人。
Tell me about this guy.
——父亲吗?-是的。
- The father? - Yeah.
哦,他是,呃…我猜他只是个普通人。
Oh, he's, er... I guess he's just your average Joe.
也许比这还多。你知道的。
Maybe a cut above. You know the type.
他工作努力，喜欢打架，喝得有点多，诸如此类。
He works hard, he likes the fights, he drinks a little too much, that... that kinda thing.
我觉得他是个…他是个很好的父亲。
I get the impression he's a... He's a pretty good father.
-至少他在努力。-男孩不喜欢他父母的哪一点?
- At least he tries to be. - What doesn't the boy like about his parents?
嗯，他们和他谈了谈，然后，呃……他们发现他……他很敌对。
Well, they had a talk with him, and, er... They found that he's, er... He's pretty hostile.
-他叫他们骗子，笨蛋…——是吗?
- He calls 'em phonies, stupid... - Are they?
不,……不是为了我的钱。不比别人多。
No, not... Not for my money. Not any more than anybody else.
至少他们在试着去理解，去改善关系，这可比那个男孩做的多得多。我的意思是……你潜水过吗?
At least they're trying to understand, to... To improve the relationship, which is a hell of a lot more than that boy is doing. I mean... You ever been skin diving?
潜水?-是的。
- Skin diving? - Yeah.
我是说，我从没想过我会和鱼交流，直到我去潜水。
I mean, I never thought I'd communicate with a fish until I went scuba diving.
你站在一个鱼缸前，盯着这条愚蠢的小鱼，它们也盯着你，然后……什么都没有。
You stand in front of one of those fish tanks, stare in at this dumb little fish, and they stare back at you, and... Nothing.
然后你进入他们的世界，在他们的世界里游来游去，他们会跟你玩捉人游戏，他们会取笑你，好像在对你咧嘴笑……他们交流。
And then you go down into their world, swim around, hell, they'll play tag with you, they'll tease you, seem to grin at you... They communicate.
有时间应该试试。
Oughta try it sometime.
现在…这个男孩到底做了什么让你和他的父母，这么生气?——不是我。我…我没有心烦意乱。
Now... What specifically did this boy do that got you, and his parents, - so upset? - Not me. I... I wasn't upset.
——而不是个人。——我明白了。
- Not personally. - I understand.
毕竟，他是他们的孩子。“……他做了什么?
After all, he's their kid. “What... what did he do?
他在家里吃了迷幻药。
Well, he took some LSD, right in the home.
——嗯。-他得了那种病，呃……——旅行。游手好闲的人。-对，就是这样。
- Mm-hmm. - He had one of those bad, er... - Trips. Bummer. - Yeah, that's it.
然后,这……他从家里跑了出来，他的父母在东村一路找到了他，他身上装着毒品，躺在床上。和一个最丑的女孩在一起…
Then, this... he ran away from home and his parents found him all the way down in the east village loaded with drugs and in bed with a... With a girl, one of the ugliest...
父母做了什么?
What did the parents do?
他们把他带回家。
They took him home.
还有什么?
What else?
就是这样。他们不知道该怎么办。
That's it. They don't know what to do.
-好的，我有一些建议给你。——太棒了。
- Okay, I've got some advice for you. - Great.
跑,不要走。
Run, don't walk.
家庭治疗。
Family therapy.
你是说送她去看心理医生吗?
You mean, send her to a psychoanalyst?
“她”?
"Her"?
我说“她”了吗?
Did I say "her"?
不,我的意思是……我的意思是“他”。
No, I meant... l meant "him".
但不要派他去。带他。
But don't send him. Take him.
家庭治疗。
Family therapy.
-父母也是吗?-最重要的是父母。
- The parents, too? - Parents, most of all.
哦,他会…他不会那样做的。
Oh, he'll... He'll never do that.
那你去和他谈谈。
Well, you talk to him.
不，我认识他。他不是那种类型的人。
No, I know him. He's not the type.
你……你要说服他。
You... you fry to convince him.
今天似乎没有人很健谈。
Nobody... Seems very talkative today.
坦白地说，医生，我觉得我们在这些会议上没什么进展。
Frankly, doctor, I don't think we were getting much done here in these sessions.
有多少人?四个吗?五个?
How many of 'em? Four? Five?
我只听说我是个大骗子。
All I've heard is what a big phoney I am.
好吧，也许我是。就我个人而言，我不认为我是。
All right, maybe I am. Personally, I don't think I am.
但是，如果我女儿想告诉我，就让她免费告诉我。
But, if my daughter wants to tell me that, let her tell me for free.
没有个人,医生。
Nothing personal, doc.
你觉得怎么样，马克西?
What do you say to that, maxie?
我…我…我不知道。
I... I... I don't know.
你一定有一些想法。
You must have some thoughts about it.
不是真的。
Not really.
你呢，gerrie?
How about you, gerrie?
嗯，我知道这很贵，但在我看来，她和我们一起来这里，坐在这里是很重要的。
Well, I... I know it is expensive, but it seems to me that just the fact that she's coming here with us, and... and... and sitting here is important.
我有选择的余地吗?
Do I have a choice?
马克西，能帮我个忙吗?
Maxie, would you do me a favour?
也许吧。
Maybe.
你每次来这里都戴着墨镜和围巾，所以我几乎看不见你。
Every time you come here, you wear those dark glasses and that scarf, so I can hardly see you.
我被动地疏远了。
I'm passively alienated.
她记住了这些该死的短语，然后就迫不及待地要用它们。
She memorises these damn phrases and then just can't wait to use 'em.
你是个漂亮的女孩。
You're a pretty girl.
我们谈话的时候能看见你会更好。
It would be nice to see you while we talk.
好多了。谢谢你！
Much better. Thank you.
马克西，你为什么觉得你爸爸是个骗子?
Maxie, why do you think your dad is a phoney?
首先，他是个追尾者。
Well, for one thing, he's a tail-chaser.
你想再解释一下吗?
Do you care to amplify that?
我见过他和一个女人在一起好几次。
I've seen him with a woman several times.
也许亚瑟有个解释。
Maybe Arthur has an explanation.
我早就知道了。
I've known for a long time.
-有证据吗?——不,我…我只是知道，仅此而已。
- By any evidence? - No, I... I just knew, that's all.
女人总是知道的。
Women always know.
有时你错了。
Sometimes you're wrong.
当我们怀疑的时候，我们可能是错的，但当我们知道的时候，我们总是对的。
Oh, when we suspect it, we can be wrong, but when we know it, then we're always right.
不总是正确的。
Not always.
总是这样。
Always.
我们是否承认这一点是另一个问题，但是……我承认了，我决定接受现实。
Whether we admit it to ourselves or not is another question, but... I did admit it, and I decided to live with it.
但是马克西不能。是吗，马克西?
But maxie couldn't. Is that right, maxie?
我才不管他做什么。
I couldn't care less what he does.
那是他的事。让他去做吧。
That's his thing. Let him do it.
就像受苦是她的事，窥探别人的事是你的事。
Just like suffering is her thing, and pryin' into other people's business is yours.
那为什么我不能在不被窃听的情况下做我自己的事呢?
So why can't I do mine without being bugged all the time about it?
你父亲在哭，马克西。
Your father's crying, maxie.
你怎么看?
What do you think about that?
嗯。
Hmm.
我不认为他能。
I didn't think he could.
现在,看…关于今天下午。我。
Now, look... Look, about this afternoon. I.
- Gerrie，我想说一件事-你什么都不用说。
- Gerrie, I'd like to say one thing. - You don't have to say anything.
该死，我知道。
Damn it, yes, I do.
你想哭就哭吧。-我不会哭的。
- You can cry if you want to. - I'm not going to cry.
好吧，随你的便。
Well, whatever you feel like.
你一定知道这不是你做了或没做的事。
You must know that it wasn't anything you did or didn't do.
-拜托，别说了。-嗯，…这只是我的一个弱点，某种该死的无用的特质……格里，没人靠近过。
- Please, stop it. - Well, it was... It was just a weakness on my part, some kind of a damned no-good streak of... Gerrie, nobody ever got close.
这不是亲密关系之类的。
It was no closeness or anything like that.
这显然是动物不负责任的本能。
It was plain, irresponsible animal instincts.
还有一件事，我一直觉得…不,两件事。
And one other thing, I always felt... no, two things.
我每次都感到羞愧，现在也是。……这是一件事。
I always felt ashamed every time, and I'm ashamed now. That's... that's one thing.
另一件事是……
And the other thing is...
另一件事是，我再也不会这么做了。
The other thing is, I'll never do it again.
我抽烟太多了。
I smoke too much.
我才不管清单上写了什么，你…——亚瑟。-我很急，黛拉
I don't give a damn what the inventory says, you... - Arthur. - I'm in a big hurry, della.
亚瑟!
Arthur!
然后，把它们拿出来，把温度提高到380,480度，接近500华氏度。
And then, to lift them out, raise the heat about 380, 480, nearly up to 500 degrees fahrenheit.
你一整天都表现得很奇怪。
You've been acting funny all day.
黛拉，我要去马戈林医生的办公室。
Della, I'm due at dr margolin's office.
阿特，去三号仓库，看看我们手头有多少个0.75吨的货。
Art, go check warehouse three, see how many three-quarter-ton units we have on hand.
我现在有四辆卡车在等这批货。
I've got four trucks waiting for this shipment right now.
你生我的气了吗?
Are you mad at me about something?
黛拉，格里知道我们的事了。
Della, gerrie knows about us.
听着，我不是要解雇你。我还是希望你在这里工作，但其他的…你最好别把我当纸巾来对待，亚瑟。
Look, now, I'm not firing you. I still want you to work here, but the rest of it... Better not try to treat me like an old kleenex, Arthur.
我…我现在不能跟你谈，黛拉。
I... I can't talk to you now, della.
回答它,混蛋。
Answer it, bastard.
看看他们都多大了。
Well, just look how old they are.
我是说，你想和这么老的人在一起吗?
I mean, how would you like to have folks that old, huh?
我只是讨厌他们，仅此而已。
I just hate 'em, that's all.
我是说，像他们这样的两个老人生孩子太蠢了。
I mean, it's dumb for two old people like them to have a baby.
他们要孩子干什么?
What would they wanna have a baby for?
我的意思是，我母亲45岁，我父亲60岁，看看他们得到了什么。我!
I mean, my mother was forty-five years old, and my father was sixty, and look what they got. Me!
看看我的样子。
Look how I look.
为什么你在生孩子之前就不能想到孩子呢?
Why couldn't you think of the kid before you started havin' a kid?
为什么他们就不能说"好吧，好吧" "我们太老了，不能生孩子了"
Why couldn't they just say, "okay, okay, "we're too old to have a baby"?
但是我的父亲。他得去证明他能有孩子。这一切都是为了他自己。
But my father. He's gotta go and prove he can have a kid. All for his own ego.
他们两个我都讨厌，我真希望他们死掉。
Well, I hate both of 'em. I wish they would just die.
我真希望我死了。
I wish I would die.
当我还想从高中毕业的时候，我甚至还没意识到他们那破旧的身体给了我多么愚蠢的大脑。
When I was still tryin' to graduate high school, before I even realised what a dumb brain they'd given me with their old beat-up bodies.
我以前很讨厌他们来学校，我尽量避免靠近他们。
I used to hate it when they'd come over to the school and I'd try and avoid being anywhere near them.
抱歉，工作上出了点小问题。
Sorry, little problem on the job.
我告诉每个人他们其实是我的祖父母。
I told everybody they were really my grandparents.
好吧，看看他们!
Well, look at 'em!
看看它们，真恶心!
Look at 'em, they're disgusting!
我是说，你想不想当个孩子，试着打棒球，有个八十岁的父亲?
I mean, how would you like to be a kid, tryin' to... tryin' to play baseball, and have a father that's eighty years old?
我恨他。
I hate him.
你知道,我……我恨你。
You know, I... I hate you.
你真是个混蛋!
You are a shit!
你为什么不去别的地方等死呢?
Why don't you just go away someplace, and... and die?
去死吧。
Just die.
嗯…谁对沃利的声明有何评论?
Well... Who has a comment on Wally's statement?
没有人吗?
Nobody?
肯定有人有话要说吧?
Well, surely somebody has something to say?
是的,我有。
Yes, I do.
-你没有权利…-我不想再听你说了。
- You've got no right... - I don't wanna listen to you again.
-你坐在那里和…-你知道，他对每件事都有评论，但他什么都不知道。
- You sit there and talk to... - You know, he's got a comment on everything, and he doesn't know anything about anything.
——但是,做……-但他刚告诉我…马克西，你有什么要说的吗?
- But, do... - But he's just told me... Do you have a comment, maxie?
是的,我有。
Yes, I do.
你不介意吧?女士优先?
You don't mind, do you? Ladies first?
来吧,马克西。
Go ahead, maxie.
首先，这些恶心的东西我看得越多，我就越不知道我为什么在这里。
Well, first of all, the more I come to these gross things, the less I know why I'm here.
我是说，这些会议真的很恶心。
I mean, these meetings are really gross.
这些小组会议有时可能会有点恶心。
Well, these group sessions might get a bit gross sometimes.
这个,呃……这个人在这里，这个…这个叫沃利的家伙，他只是在浪费我们的时间。他是个疯子。
This, um... This person over here, this... This Wally guy, he just wastes our time. He's a nut.
这个可爱的大宝贝呢?
What about this sweet big baby?
在各个领域都是权威。
Big authority on every subject.
他真让我恶心。
Well, he makes me sick.
你们都让我恶心。
You all make me sick.
如果我有一些酸，…我就在此时此地把它扔了。
If I had some acid, I'd... I'd drop it right here, right now.
——“放弃”?-意思是“接受”。
- "Drop it"? - It means "take it".
你明白我的意思吗?嗯…我不想再回到这里了。
D'you see what I mean? Well... I don't wanna come back here anymore.
-你想干什么，马克西?——出来。我要出去了。
- What do you want, maxie? - Out. I want out.
你是说我们的世界?
Of our world, you mean?
是的，我会找到新的现实。
Yes, I'm gonna find a new reality.
——用药物。——是的。
- With drugs. - Yup.
但是让我们想一下。
But let's think about this a moment.
不是逃离现实世界，逃离现实……这难道不是一种死亡吗?
Isn't running away from the world as it is, away from reality... Isn't that a kind of death?
死亡有什么不好?
Well, what's so bad about death?
这能帮我们摆脱困境。
It'd get us out of this.
你好,马克西。你好吗?
Hello, maxie. How are you?
看。
Watch it.
谢谢你！原谅我。
Thank you. Excuse me.
你喜欢吗?
D'you like that?
嘿，这是新的吗?
Hey, is this new?
-你从哪儿弄来的?-我买了。
- Where'd you get it? - I bought it.
不!你知道我不能喝酒。
No! You know I can't drink.
别这样，这是庆祝，亲爱的。
Come on, it's a celebration, sweetheart.
看看她，和一个理发的男孩跳舞。
Look at her, dancing with a boy with a haircut.
一个喜欢上学的男孩。
A boy who likes school.
她需要的只是健康的家庭娱乐。
All she needed was a little wholesome family fun.
加油！加油
Come on, come on.
亚瑟!
Arthur!
——亚瑟……亚瑟!-不，我们走。
- Arthur... Arthur! - No, let's go.
漂亮!
Beautiful!
我整晚都是怎么做到的?
How did I ever do that all night long?
你在抽什么?
What's that you're smoking?
草,男人。
Grass, man.
-你想来点吗?-你在开玩笑吗?
- You want some? - Are you kiddin"?
让我看看。
Let me see that.
嘿，嘿，怎么了?我做了什么?
Hey, hey, what's the matter? What did I do?
发生什么事了?
What's... what's goin' on?
嘿,阻止他!
Hey, stop him!
-住手!-在我家里抽大麻!
- Break it up! - Smokin' pot in my house!
你对吧?是的。
You all right? Yes.
他只是有点，呃……加载,仅此而已。
He's just a little, er... Loaded, that's all.
我很抱歉。我很抱歉。
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
你不该这么刻薄，亚瑟。
You shouldn't have been so mean, Arthur.
也许我们都应该试试。
Well, maybe we all oughta try it.
我听说它不会让你宿醉，不像马提尼酒。
I hear it doesn't give you a hangover, the way Martinis do.
你是美丽的,蒂娜。
You're beautiful, Tina.
-我们应该考虑走了。——为什么?它的早期。
- We should think about going. - Why? It's early.
来吧，我们走。
Come on, let's go.
-我伤到你了吗?——不,男人。
- Did I hurt you? - No, man.
我希望不是这样。晚安，晚安。
I hope not. Good night, good night.
我们得说晚安了，亚瑟。
Well, we'll have to say good night, Arthur.
-是啊，我娶了个扫兴的人。-晚安，大卫。
- Yeah, I married a wet blanket. - Good night, David.
——谢谢,亚瑟。-那是什么，扫兴的人?
- Thanks, Arthur. - What's that, killjoy?
哦!轮胎链。
Oh! Tyre chains.
桑迪，桑迪，过来谢谢梅森先生给你的轮胎链。
Sandy, Sandy, come thank mr Mason for your tyre chains.
——哦,哇!-我该付你多少钱?
- Oh, wow! - Oh, how much do I owe you?
——忘记它。——不,不。
- Forget it. - No, no.
我真的很感激你，梅森先生。
Hey, I really appreciate these, mr Mason.
来，把钥匙给我。我把它们放在你的行李箱里。
Here, let me have your keys. I'll put 'em in your trunk for you.
别傻了，妈妈，我来。
Oh, don't be silly, mom, I'll do it.
不,不,不。你待在这里玩得开心。
No, no, no. You stay here and have fun.
——没有。——是的,先生。
- No. - Yes, sir.
你都还没喝呢。
You haven't even had your drink yet.
他觉得如果他今晚不喝酒，也许我会让他…再见!
He thinks if he doesn't drink his drink tonight, maybe I'll let him have... bye!
也许我明天会让他吃两个。
Maybe I'll let him have two tomorrow.
说实话，妈妈，我真的不想要。
To tell you the truth, mom, I really don't want it.
现在,卑鄙,卑鄙。
Now, sneaky, sneaky.
把钥匙给我。
Let me have your keys.
可能是和某个女孩走了，然后被困在雪地里。
Probably go off with some girl, and get stuck in the snow.
你会相信那个男孩吗?
Huh, would you believe that boy?
他总有一天会娶那辆车。
He's gonna marry that car someday.
他想娶什么就娶什么。
Oh, well, he can marry anything he wants.
只要他在院长的名单上，我们就不在乎，对吧，亲亲?
As long as he's on the Dean's list, we don't care, do we, smoochie?
你好,在那里。
Hi, there.
老家伙麻烦，我不需要你J我只想你离我的门远点J只要你离我的门远点J现在，我有节奏J我有音乐J我有我的女人
J old man trouble, I don't need you j I just want you to stay away from my door j just you stay away from my door j now, I got rhythm j I got music j I've got my gal
谁能要求更多?她玩得很开心，亲爱的。她有一个真正的老式舞会。
j who could ask for anything more? J she had a ball, sweetheart. She had a real old-fashioned ball.
你也一样。
And so did you.
马克西!
Maxie!
哦,马克西。
Oh, maxie.
在我看来，你女儿受了很大的伤害。
In my judgement, your daughter has taken a large dose of stp.
Stp吗?那不是很危险的那个吗?
Stp? Isn't that the one that's so dangerous?
-亲爱的…-是的，可以。
- Sweetheart... - It can be, yes.
我们没有解毒剂。
We have no antidote for stp.
我们可以试着让那个人安静下来，等它消失。
We can just try to keep the person quiet and wait till it wears off.
我建议你回家休息一下。
I suggest you go home and try to get some rest.
医生……十点钟回来。
Doctor... Come back at ten o'clock.
是的,但是……
Yes, but...
你觉得桑迪为什么不让我拿他的车钥匙?
Why do you suppose Sandy wouldn't let me have the keys to his car?
大卫吗?
David?
蒂娜，看在上帝的份上!
Tina, for Pete's sake!
那些减肥药让你变得完全古怪。
Those diet pills are making you downright kooky.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
你喝得够多的了，现在看看你。
You had enough to drink to put a horse to sleep, and now look at ya.
我没办法。
I can't help it.
你拿这个干什么?
What are you doing with this?
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我卖它。
I'm selling it.
大卫……
David...
现在,看看。
Now, look.
孩子们在吃这些东西。
The kids are taking this stuff.
我是说，不是我，而是很多其他人。
I mean, not me, but a lot of the others.
马克西从你那拿到的。
Maxie got it from you.
他们总得从别人那里买，对吧?
Well, they gotta buy it from somebody, right?
那么，为什么不是我呢?
So, why not me?
再说，你认为我能用你给我的那点可怜的零用钱买校服吗?
Besides, do you think I can get along and buy school clothes on that lousy little allowance you give me?
那可怜的零用钱是你父亲的命根子。
That lousy little allowance is your father's life blood.
你从节俭和储蓄中得到乐趣。
You get a kick outta scrimping and saving.
你总是。
You always have.
那你要我怎么去买汽油，在周末来回跑?
And how do you expect me to buy gas, to get back and forth on the weekends?
这很简单。这没什么。
And this is easy. There's nothing to it.
直到你被捕。
Till you get arrested.
不，警察几乎睁一只眼闭一只眼。
No, the cops almost look the other way.
……太多了，他们很尴尬。
There's... there's so much of it, they're embarrassed.
如果他们想把所有的草头都抓起来，他们就会把自己的孩子送进监狱。
If they tried to bust all the grass-heads, they'd be putting their own kids in jail.
你不怕我们逮捕你吗?
Aren't you afraid that we might have you arrested?
我了解你，爸爸。
I know you, pop.
我是你的宠儿。
I'm your fair-haired boy.
这是你人生中最大的乐趣，告诉所有人我有多棒，我有一天会成为一名大律师。
That's the biggest kick you have in life, telling everybody how great I am, how I'm gonna be a big lawyer someday.
你是对的。我是。
And you're right. I am.
你不会搞砸的。任何东西。
You wouldn't bust that up. Not for anything.
你接受不了。
You couldn't take it.
所以，在某种程度上，这是……我很幸运，你发现了。
So, in a way, it's, er... lucky for me that you found out.
因为，既然你知道了，你就算是同谋了。
Because, now that you know, you'd be sort of... Accomplices.
我可以把东西放在家里。
And I can keep the stuff right here in the house.
总之，我讨厌偷偷摸摸。
I... I hate sneaking, anyhow.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
哦,哇。
Oh, wow.
我真的害怕。你这么激动，我是说。
I really am. That you're so shook up, I mean.
不,大卫。不是警察。不是现在。
No, David. Not the police. Not now.
我们得有时间思考。
We have to have time to think.
总得有人从某个地方开始。
Somebody has to start somewhere.
-东三街178号-东第七街158号。
- 178 east 3rd street. - 158 east 7th street.
你这样浪费时间真是太可惜了。
It's a shame for you to be wasting your time like this.
那个警官刚刚侵犯了我的权利。
That officer just violated my rights.
他们会马上放我走的。
They'll let me go immediately.
作为一个公民，我觉得你可以更好地利用你的时间——努力抓住罪犯。——走吧。我们走吧。
As a citizen, I feel you could make better use of your time - trying to catch criminals. - Let's go. Let's go.
他们真的有必要派你们四个人去吗?
Did they really have to send four of you guys?
我们已经派人去请了一位同伴来陪她。
We've sent for a peer to come sit with her.
——一个同伴吗?-是的，同辈，平等的人。
- A peer? - Yes, a peer, an equal.
某人,呃…他们觉得自己值得信任。
Someone, er... they feel they can trust.
你可以这么说，不是当权派的人。
Someone not of the establishment, if you will.
正如我们所说，这个同伴帮助我们说服他们。
And this peer helps us by talking them down, as we say.
这就是所谓的精神病院，不是吗?
This is what they call a psycho ward, isn't it?
是的，一个不幸的名字。
Yes, an unfortunate name.
同样不幸的是，由于空间和人员的原因，我们不得不把像你女儿这样的小女孩和吸毒成瘾的人，所有能想到的都放在同一个病房里。
It's also unfortunate that, for space and personnel reasons, we have to put a young girl like your daughter in the same ward with... Dt cases, heroin addicts who have oded, everything imaginable.
哦，就一句警告。
Oh, just one word of warning.
她看到你在这里可能会有不良反应。
She may have an adverse reaction to seeing you here.
也许我们不该进去。
Well, maybe we shouldn't go in.
不，不，我想看看她的反应，但如果她见你不高兴你也别难过。
No, no, I'd like to see her reaction, but don't be upset if she doesn't seem glad to see you.
嗯?
Huh?
早上好。
Good morning.
——你好,医生。——早上,詹妮弗。
- Hi, doctor. - Morning, Jennifer.
我想问一件事。
I wanted to ask one thing.
我们能不能试着跟她谈谈，告诉她我们错了什么?
Would it be all right if we tried to talk to her, and tell her we were wrong about something?
对不起,我的意思是。
Apologise, I mean.
你觉得这样可以吗?
Do you think it would be all right?
尽管试试吧。
Try it, by all means.
如果她愿意接受，可能会有很大帮助。
If she's receptive, it could be a big help.
哒哒哒哒哒哒dum哒哒哒dum哒哒哒dum哒哒哒dum哒哒哒dum哒哒哒dum哒哒哒j -马克西?
J la da da Dee da Dee dum j la da da Dee da Dee dum j la da da Dee da Dee dum j dum, Dee da da dum j la da da Dee da Dee dum j la da da Dee da Dee dum y Dee dum... j - maxie?
马克西。
Maxie.
马克西,我们……我们发现了桑迪的事。
Maxie, we... We found out about Sandy.
他向他的父母承认了这一点。
He admitted it to his mother and father.
我们为指控你哥哥而道歉。
We want to apologise for... For accusing your brother.
我们知道你有多爱他…
We know how much you love him...
亚瑟!
Arthur!
萨拉查医生!拿钥匙!
Get dr Salazar! Get the key!
——他来了。-把我弄出去!让我出去!
- He's coming. - Get me out! Get me out!
嘿,妈妈。阿蒂!
Hey, mom. Artie!
我得离开这里。
I've gotta get out of here.
我听说她情绪失控了。
I heard she flipped out pretty bad.
那么你是，呃…Whatchamacallit吧?
So you're the, er... Whatchamacallit, huh?
…同行吗?
The... the peer?
他们说她要见我。
They said she asked for me.
我对你犯了个严重的错误，阿迪。
I made a pretty bad mistake about you, Artie.
这就是生活。
That's life.
帮助她康复。
Help her get better.
我试试看。
I'll try.
医生。
Doctor.
马克西。
Maxie.
我会给你做一顿让你永生难忘的晚餐。
I'm gonna fix you a dinner you won't soon forget.
我可以做晚饭。
I can fix dinner.
你呆在床上。完整的休息。
You stay in that bed. Complete rest.
你知道，我是个不错的厨师。
I'm not a bad cook, you know.
我不是。
I'm not.
是的,你是。
Yes, you are.
-拜托，马克西。-你能做到的。
- Come on, maxie. - You can do it.
来吧。
Come on.
来吧,现在。
Come on, now.
马克西吗?
Maxie?
好吧，现在你试试。
Okay, now you try it.
来吧。
Come on.
天啊，医生，这活儿真辛苦。
Jesus, doc, that's rough work.
我很快就会回来的，妹妹。
I'll be back again soon, sis.
你哥哥说帮你的工作很辛苦，你确实是，你知道吗?
Your brother says you are rough work, and you are, you know?
呵呀!
Ach!
也许我们应该带你出去转转。
Maybe we should walk you around outside for a while.
那是一个美丽的…
It's a beautiful...
你喜欢它吗?
You like it?
是的，非常好。
Yes, it's very nice.
诚实和真正的吗?
Honest and truly?
诚实的。
Honest.
这是你的。
It's yours.
这些也可以给你。我讨厌他们。
You can have these, too. I hate 'em.
你恨他们吗?
You hate 'em?
恨他们，恨他们，恨他们。
Hate 'em, hate 'em, hate 'em.
如果你恨他们，为什么要恨他们?
Well, if you hate 'em, why do 'em?
为了取悦萨拉查医生。
To please dr Salazar.
如果我愿意，萨拉查医生会放我出去的。
If I please dr Salazar, he'll let me out of here.
那太好了，宝贝。
Oh, that'll be wonderful, baby.
也许能赶上你的生日?
Maybe in time for your birthday?
我们都很想让你和我们一起回家。
We both want you back home with us so much.
哦，是吗?
Oh, you do, huh?
你会很开心的，宝贝。
You're gonna be happy, baby.
事情正在回到……好了,再在一起。
Things are getting back to... Well, together again.
过去几周，阿迪经常来。
Artie drops by more, a lot more, the last couple of weeks.
-还有你妈妈和我…-她还在床上?
- And your mom and me... - She's still in bed?
——好吧,她是……——她是胆小鬼。
- Well, she's... - She's chicken.
我讨厌胆小鬼。
I hate chicken people.
但是…但是…我想回家。我真的。
But... but... I wanna come home. I really do.
我是说，如果萨拉查医生认为我不想回家，那他就不会让我出去了。
I mean, if dr Salazar ever thought that I... That I didn't want to come home, why... Why, then he'd never let me out of here.
爸爸……
Daddy...
-你喜欢吗?——非常。
- You like this? - Very much.
它和这个是一样的。
It's just the same as this one.
爸爸，你觉得它们好吗?
Daddy, do you think they're good?
我的意思是……真的好吗?
I mean... Really good?
嗯，我认为他们很好。
Well, I think they're good.
我是说，我不是…我不是艺术评论家，但我…我认为他们展示了天赋，是的。
I mean, I'm not... I'm not an art critic, but I... I think they show talent, yes.
你真的很喜欢撒谎，是吧，爸爸?
You really like to lie a lot, don't you, daddy?
我只…知道我为什么不想回家了吧?
I only... See why I don't wanna come home?
谎言,谎言,谎言!
Lies, lies, lies!
爸爸，别告诉萨拉查医生是我说的。
Oh, daddy, don't tell dr Salazar I said that.
求你了，我真的想回家。
Please, please, I do wanna come home.
-别告诉他，爸爸，求你了-我不会。
- Don't tell him, daddy, please. - I won't.
不管怎样，我真的想回家和你和妈妈在一起。
Anyway, really, I do wanna come home and be with you and mom.
那太好了，宝贝。太棒了。
That'd be wonderful, baby. Just wonderful.
我愿意，我愿意，我愿意……我愿意。
I do, I do, I do... I do.
我愿意。
I do.
爸爸……你为什么要我回家?
Daddy... Why do you want me to come home?
为什么?
Why?
因为我们爱你，这就是原因。
Because we love you, that's why.
骗子,骗子。
Liar, liar.
-骗子，骗子，骗子，骗子!-马克西，别这样。
- Liar, liar, liar, liar, liar! - Maxie, please don't.
——我很抱歉。——骗子!
- I'm sorry. - Liar!
-我不是故意惹你生气的。——骗子!
- I didn't mean to get you upset. - Liar!
不,马克西,请!
Don't, maxie, please!
——足够,马克西。——这就够了。
- Enough, maxie. - That's enough.
对不起,我……我下周不能见你了。
I'm sorry, I... I won't be able to see you next week.
我要出城了。
I'll be outta town.
但你妈妈可以打电话。
But your mother can call.
-告诉她不用麻烦了。-她不能下床
- Tell her not to bother. - She's not allowed out of bed.
请走开!走开!
Go away, please! Go away!
我将……十天后见，宝贝。
I'll... I'll see you in about ten days, baby.
他让我很紧张。
He just gets me uptight.
我有权利紧张，就像其他人一样。
I have a right to get uptight, just like anybody else.
这并不意味着我有什么问题。
It doesn't mean there's anything wrong with me.
亚瑟，这些事非得在星期天做吗?
Arthur, does this stuff have to be done on a Sunday?
当然必须这么做。我告诉你。
'Course it has to be done. I told ya.
我是说，为什么是我?
I mean, why me?
"为什么是我"是什么意思?"
Whaddaya mean, "why me?"
这么晚了我还能找谁知道空调的规格?
Who else could I get who knows about air condition specifications at this late date?
没有人,我猜。
Nobody, I guess.
你到底是怎么回事?
What the hell's the matter with you?
你穿成这样是为了什么?
And what are you all dressed up for?
星期天我总是盛装打扮。
I always dress up on Sunday.
亚瑟，你真的以为拉弗蒂会同意市政府工作的新规格，结果他告发了你吗?
Arthur, is it really true that you expected Rafferty to okay the new specs on this city job, and he finked out on you?
当你了解一个人的时候，你会觉得他们会屈服。
You get to know somebody, you'd think they'd bend a little.
如果我不能在明天早上9点的截止日期前完成这些新规格…-他们会取消合同。
And if I don't reach the nine A.M. deadline tomorrow - with these new specs... - They'd cancel the contract.
你会失去什么呢?
And you'd lose?
这是我想过的最重要的工作，黛拉。
This is the biggest job I ever figured, della.
根据我的计算，你将损失大约1700美元的开支和大约1万美元的预期利润。
By my calculations, you'll lose about seventeen hundred dollars expenditures and about ten thousand dollars expected profits.
这是正确的。
That's right.
我不干了,亚瑟。
I quit, Arthur.
从现在开始。
As of now.
你在开玩笑!
You're kiddin"!
回头见。
Ta-ta.
黛拉，你不能这么做!
Della, you can't do this!
想打赌吗?
Wanna bet?
在这种时候是不行的。
Not at a time like this.
我一直在等待这样的时刻，亚瑟。
A time like this is what I've been waiting for, Arthur.
我们做得怎么样了?
Well, how are we doing?
她不和我说话。
She won't talk to me.
也许下次。
Maybe next time.
再见,医生。
So long, doctor.
我想离开这里，我不想跟他们回去。
I want out of here, and I don't wanna go back with them.
我不明白为什么我要等到十八岁。
And I don't see why I have to wait till I'm eighteen.
孩子们知道的比法律制定时多得多。
Kids know a lot more than they used to when that law was made.
-关于一些事情。——关于一切。
- About some things. - About everything.
总之，关于重要的事情。
Anyway, about important things.
自我保护很重要吗?
Is self-preservation an important thing?
这是个棘手的问题，我不会回答的。
That's a trick question, and I'm not going to answer it.
好吧。
All right.
假设你父母现在让你自由了，让你自己生活。
Let's suppose your parents let you go free right now, be on your own.
他们也可以。14个月后，当我18岁的时候，我无论如何都会去做，所以他们也可以。
They might as well. In fourteen months, when I'm eighteen, I'm gonna do it anyhow, so they might as well.
好吧，让我们假设他们有。你会怎么做?
All right, let's suppose they do. What would you do?
我是说，你会如何安排你的生活?
I mean, how would you arrange your life?
嗯…首先，我会和我的男朋友来一次长途旅行。
Well... First, I'd take a long trip with my boyfriend.
-为什么是长途旅行?-因为我从来没有长途旅行过。
- Why a long one? - Because I never had a long one.
我从来没有足够的钱去旅行。
I never had enough bread for that much stuff.
你怎么称呼“长途旅行”?
What would you call "a long trip"?
大约一个星期。
About a week.
但如果你以前没有钱，你怎么能期望现在有呢?
But if you didn't have the money before, how would you expect to have it now?
我不知道。在某种程度上。
I don't know. Somehow.
你还想谈些什么?
What else would you like to talk about?
我什么时候能离开这里?
When do I get out of here?
我们正在努力。
We're working on that.
。
Oh.
今天下午我又和她谈过了。她……还在封闭自己。
I talked to her again this afternoon. She's... Still on the other side of a stone wall.
但她已经进步了。
But she has improved.
萨拉查医生说。
Dr Salazar said that.
“稳步改善。”
"Steady improvement."
-他是这么说的，不是吗?——这是正确的。
- That's what he said, isn't it? - That's right.
我告诉他你今天睡了一段时间，他说他肯定你会恢复的很好，亲爱的。
And I told him you were up for a while today, and he said he was sure you'd snap back just fine, sweetheart.
有时你会想自己是否想要恢复。
Sometimes you wonder if you want to snap back.
他知道……他能估计她还要在那里待多久吗?多可怕的说法啊。
Does he know yet... Can he estimate how much longer she'll have to be in this... What a hideous way of saying it.
这种“受控环境”?
This "controlled environment"?
不,不。我也问了他同样的问题。
No, no. I asked him the same thing.
它只是取决于。他们……他们没有办法知道，直到他们有更多的时间。
It just depends. They... They have no way of knowing until they have more time.
但真正让我烦恼的是，这一切都归结为钱。
But what really bugs me is it all boils down to money.
我想一切都是迟早的事。
I guess everything does, sooner or later.
他们有私人医院，在那里他们可以得到最好的治疗，每个病人大约有两名工作人员，有大量的治疗，一切都是最好的。
They've got these private hospitals where they get the best possible care, where they have about two staff members per patient, plenty of therapy, everything of the best.
那就是马克西应该去的地方。
Well, that's where maxie's got to be.
是的，我就是这么说的。
Yeah, that's what I said.
但是这些地方大约要…你准备好了吗?
But these places run from about... Are you ready for this?
每年2.5万到4万。
Twenty-five to forty thousand a year.
- 25 ?-每年四万。
- Twenty-five? - To forty thousand a year.
-但没人能负担得起。-我们不能，那很简单。
- But nobody can afford that. - We can't, that's a cinch.
还有什么呢?
Well, what else is there?
在那之后，它就会下降很多。
After that, it just drops way off.
你……你进入公共场所。
You... You get into the public places.
最糟糕的是，在大多数市政机构中并没有专门为这类事情设立的地方。
And the worst part of it is, they don't really have a place just specifically for this kinda thing in most municipal institutions.
我是说，她会和瘾君子呆在一起，你知道的，海洛因瘾君子，精神分裂症患者……好吧,那是不可能的。我们不能把她放在那样的地方。
I mean, she'd be in with addicts, ya know, heroin addicts, schizophrenes... Well, that's impossible. We can't put her in anything like that.
我知道。
I know.
亚瑟，他们确定吗?
Arthur, are they sure?
我们就不能在家里再试一次吗?
I mean, couldn't we try it just once more at home?
三位专家和她谈过，他们都建议不要这么做。
Three specialists talked to her and they all recommended against it.
他们都认为她有很强的自我毁灭的冲动。
They all agree she has very strong self-destructive urges.
我们就不能把她安置在那种昂贵的地方吗，就六个月?我们能负担得起六个月。
Well, couldn't we put her in one of these expensive places, just for six months? We could afford six months.
亚瑟，你不能把他们说的都告诉我。
Arthur, you're not telling me everything they said.
亲爱的，他们认为她可能永远需要这个受控制的环境。
Sweetheart, they think she may be in need of this controlled environment... Indefinitely.
你不会是说她的余生吧?
You don't mean for the rest of her life?
这是有可能的。
It's possible.
我问他们如果我们放了她会怎么样，他们说她最终可能会自杀。
I asked them what would happen if we just let her go free, and they said she'd probably destroy herself eventually.
我说，嗯，我现在的感觉是，与其把她埋在什么机构里，我还不如让她走出去，按她自己的意愿给自己下药致死，然后再把她埋了。
I said, well, the way I feel now, instead of burying her in some institution, I'd just as soon let her go out and drug herself to death the way she wants to, and then bury her.
但那就是放弃了，我们不会放弃的。
But that'd be quitting, and we're not gonna quit.
不，先生，有办法的。
No, no, sir. There's a way.
她很有可能会康复。
There's a good chance she can get well.
他们说。他们都同意这一点。这是……这是我们必须坚持的。
They said that. They all agreed on that. That's... That's what we have to hang onto.
哦,来……来吧，亲爱的。
Oh, come... Come on, now, sweetheart.
亲爱的，你知道萨拉查说了什么吗?
Sweetheart, you know what Salazar said?
他说她根本不恨我们。
He said she doesn't really hate us at all.
他的解释是，她已经长大了，可以看到我们的错误，但还没有成熟到可以原谅它们。
The way he explained it is, she's grown old enough to see our faults, but just not mature enough yet to forgive them.
听着，别想这个了，亲爱的。
Look, try not to think about it, sweetheart.
你想要点什么吗?
Do you want anything?
也许你应该在晚饭前小睡一下。
Maybe you oughta take a nap before dinner.
就是这样!
That's it!
等着看我给你准备了什么晚餐吧。
Wait till you see what I've got you for dinner.
阿迪也要来吃晚饭，你知道的。
Artie's coming to dinner too, ya know.
来吧,现在。你打个盹。
Come on, now. You take a nap.
我来了。
I'm coming.
来了。
Coming.
——亚瑟,你好。——噢,大卫。
- Arthur, hi. - Oh, David.
-我能进来吗?-拜托，进来吧，进来吧。
- Can I come in? - Oh, please, come on, come on in, yes.
亚瑟，你知道桑迪已经被保释了，我们一直在等待审判日期…我知道你和蒂娜也经历过这事。
Well, Arthur, you know Sandy's been out on bail, and we've been waiting for a trial date... I know you and Tina have suffered through this thing, too.
好吧，听着，我们刚得到消息，呃…我要你试着冷静下来，亚瑟。
Yeah, well, listen, we just got word, er... I want you to try to be calm, Arthur.
我们刚得到消息，指控已经撤销了。
We just got word that the charges have been dropped.
——一些,呃……——撤销?
- Some, er... - Dropped?
是的，技术性的，非法搜查和扣押。-你是说，完全不惩罚?
Yes, technicalities, - illegal search and seizure. - You mean, no punishment at all?
我知道你的感受，亚瑟。
Now, I know how you feel, Arthur.
这件事我也很难过，为了你。听……——不!不!-等一下
I've been very upset about this thing, too, for you. Listen... - No! No! - Now, wait a minute.
等一下，亚瑟!
Wait a minute, Arthur!
-从车里出来!——梅森先生!嘿!的帮助!
- Get outta that car! - Mr Mason! Hey! Help!
我女儿在收容所里，你以为你能自由走动吗?不!不!
My daughter's in an institution, and you think you'll walk around free? No! No!
不!上帝,不!
No! By god, no!
……他疯了!疯了!他疯了!
He's... he's crazy! Crazy! He's going crazy!
亚瑟!亚瑟!
Arthur! Arthur!
-不，我们看看你是否…——爸爸!
- No, we'll see if you... - Dad!
爸爸!快点，爸爸，快点。
Dad! Come on, dad, come on.
这对谁都没好处。我要杀了他!
That's not gonna do anybody any good. I'll kill him!
我要杀了他，这婊子!你的…-你听到了。-他想杀我!
I'll kill him, the cunt! Your... - You heard him. - He tried to kill me!
你是我的证人。
You're my witnesses.
我要报警，他会被逮捕的。
I'm calling the police, and he's going to be arrested.
我知道我的权利!
I know my rights!
我一直认为自己不会使用暴力，但如果你再对你的权利发出一个下流的声音，你玷污了我的生活，我就会伤害你。
I have always thought of myself as incapable of violence, but if you make one more obscene sound about your rights, you pollution of my life, I shall hurt you.
-我会伤害你的。-来吧，放开我。
- I shall hurt you. - Come on, let go, now.
告诉他我要打断他的背!
Tell him I'll break his back!
好了，我现在没事了。我们走吧。
All right, I'm all right now. Let's go.
天啊，希望你妈妈没听到。
God, I hope your mother didn't hear.
-天啊，我气炸了!-只有你能。
- Christ, I really blew! - As only you can.
虚伪的小混蛋。“案件驳回。”
Slimy little bastard. "Case dismissed."
可怜的大卫，有个那样的孩子。
Poor David, with a kid like that.
天啊，他病得比…嗯,你在这里!
Christ, he's sicker than... Well, you're here!
-我买了一些中国菜当晚餐。-是的。
- I bought some Chinese food for dinner. - Yeah.
粤菜龙虾"飞虱"什么的。
Lobster cantonese, "flied lice", the whole deal.
-你说什么?——好吧,太棒了!
- Whaddaya say? - Well, great!
好。
Good.
亲爱的，我们有客人了!
Sweetheart, we've got a guest!
她在哪里呢?她可能在浴室里打扮呢。
Where is she? She's probably in the bathroom, primping.
她现在可以起床几分钟了。
She can get up for a few minutes now.
我想喝一杯。你呢?
I could use a drink. How about you?
——嗯…-你知道吗，我想我们这辈子都没一起喝过酒，就我们两个人。
- Well... - You know, I don't think we've ever had a drink together, just the two of us, in all our lives.
-你说什么?——嗯,好吧。
- Whaddaya say? - Yeah, okay.
…我不记得是谁告诉我的，但他说，""如果你喝酒是为了消遣，你就抿一小口，"但如果你真的需要喝一杯，那就是工作，你绝不在工作上浪费时间。"
I don't... you know, I don't remember who told me this, but he said that, "if you're drinking for pleasure, you sip it, "but if you really need a drink, that's business,and you never waste time in business." - That's right.
你打算怎么处理你的?嗯…快点，快点，别犹豫。
What are you gonna do with yours? Well... Come on, come on, don't hesitate.
不喝就输了。
He who does is lost.
喝下去，就是这样。
Down the hatch, that's it.
你不觉得好点了吗?
There, doesn't that make you feel better?
现在，我们上去看看你妈妈吧。来吧。
Now, let's go up and see your mom. Come on.
我把你收到的所有邀请都告诉她了，她很自豪。
I told her about all the offers you were getting, and she was very proud.
正好向你展示了我对音乐的了解。
Just goes to show you what I know about music.
什么都没有。
Nothing.
阿迪，别把广东龙虾的事告诉你妈。我想给她个惊喜。
Listen, Artie, don't say anything to your mother about the lobster cantonese. I wanna surprise her.
甜心?
Sweetheart?
Gerrie吗?
Gerrie?
她不在这里。
She's not here.
晚上好。我是梅森夫人，马克西的母亲。
Good evening. I'm mrs Mason, maxie's mother.
恐怕探视时间已经过去了，梅森夫人。
Oh, I'm afraid visiting hours are over, mrs Mason.
萨拉查医生说没问题。
Dr Salazar said it was all right.
一定是搞错了。
Well, there must be some mistake.
-他从不那样做。-不，不，这是件特别的事。
- He never does that. - No, no, it's a special thing.
如果你不介意的话，我得给他打个电话。
Well, if you don't mind, I've gotta call him.
嗯，他不在家。
Well, he's not at home.
我丈夫和我刚和他们吃过晚饭，然后他们就去看电影了。
My husband and I just had dinner with them, and they went on to a movie.
梅森太太，没有他的同意我不能这么做。
Mrs Mason, I can't do it without his consent.
我将承担全部责任。
I'll take full responsibility.
毕竟，我是她的母亲。
After all, I am her mother.
你看，…这是现实疗法的一个实验。
You see, it's a... It's an experiment in reality therapy.
——“现实疗法”?-是的，没错。
- "Reality therapy"? - Yes, that's correct.
-嗯，我想…-我去叫她来，梅森太太。
- Well, I suppose... - I'll go get her for you, mrs Mason.
您可以在那边的候诊室等着，梅森夫人。
You can wait in the waiting room there, mrs Mason.
马克西。
Maxie.
没事的，马克西。
It's all right, maxie.
你一直拒绝我的电话。
You've been refusing my calls.
你父亲告诉我他来的时候你不和他说话。
Your father tells me you won't speak to him when he comes here.
这是你惩罚我们的方式。
That's your way of punishing us.
好吧，我不怪你
All right, I don't blame you.
他们很快就会放你出去了。
They're going to let you out of here pretty soon.
你只能靠自己了。自由,完全自由。
You'll be on your own. Free, totally free.
至少，你是这么想的。
At least, that's what you think.
但我知道真相。
But I know the truth.
事实是你会永远待在这里。
The truth is that you're going to be here forever.
哦，在这里不行，因为他们不能让你在这里待太久，也不能让你住那种每年两万五千美元的豪华公寓，因为我们负担不起。
Oh, not here, because they can't keep you here much longer, and not in one of those luxury places for twenty-five thousand dollars a year, because we can't afford that.
终于，有些东西，终于，我们给不起你了。
Finally, there's something, finally, that we can't afford to give you.
你看不出这有什么好笑的，对吧?
You don't see the humour in that, do you?
我也不知道。
Well, neither do I.
所以他们会把你关在一个地方，一个不太好的地方，恐怕，永远。
So they're going to keep you some place, some not very nice place, I'm afraid, forever.
或者，即使不是永远，也是很长一段时间。
Or, if not forever, for a very long time.
你知道为什么吗?你知道吗?
Do you know why? Do you?
不知?
No?
那我来告诉你。
Then I'll tell you.
因为你宁愿因为我们是人类而惩罚我们也不愿努力恢复健康。
Because you'd rather punish us for being human than try to get well.
因为你还是个大孩子，如果游戏不按你的方式玩，你就不会玩了。
Because you're still a big baby, and if the game's not played your way, you're not gonna play at all.
我是来告诉你，你逃不掉的。
Well, I'm here to tell you that you're not gonna get away with it.
作为你的母亲，我告诉你，你会活下来的。
I'm telling you, as your mother, that you are going to survive.
你要跟我说话，你就能活下来。
You're going to speak to me, and you're going to survive.
现在，转过来，看着我。
Now, turn around here, and look at me.
我说"看我"!
I said, "look at me"!
告诉我你会好起来的。
Now, tell me you're going to get well.
说!
Say it!
说你会努力。
Say you'll try.
说!
Say it!
-说你会努力。说!——Gerrie !Gerrie !
- Say you'll try. Say it! - Gerrie! Gerrie!
变迁之风，呼唤我的名字&
J winds of change, they call my name &
我们走吧,马克西。
Let's go, maxie.
然后招手，“来吧”
J and beckon, "come"
就像飞蛾扑火一样
j just like a moth to a flame
神奇轮在哪里?
j and wherein lies the wonderwheel?
- &'我们都被安排好了如何去感受- Gerrie，听我说，好吗?Gerrie……哦，妈妈，你不要等我，哦，妈妈
- &' we've all been structured how to feel & - Gerrie, listen to me, will you? Gerrie... J oh, mama j don't you wait up for me j oh, mama
我要去看看这个世界
J I'm off to see the world j